payzone.ie 2019-03-17

# Privacy Policy - Payzone

**Introduction**

At Payzone, we are committed to protecting the privacy of our customers and keeping your details secure. This means that we’ll protect the personal information (“Data”) of all visitors who access our websites or services through any platform or device (collectively, the “Site”).

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) explains how Payzone collect, share, and use your personal information. You’ll also find information about how you can exercise your privacy rights. By using our Services you agree to Payzone using your Data as described in this Privacy Policy.

This website from now on referred to as the (“Site”), is operated by Payzone Ireland Limited (Payzone). This Privacy Policy together with our Terms and Conditions and Cookie Policy provides guidance and information to users/visitors of the Site regarding the processing of Personal Data (Data) by Payzone.

In this Privacy Policy references to “You” means the person whose Data we collect, use and process.

We wish to help you make informed decisions, so please take a few moments to read the sections below and learn how we may use your Data.

**Acceptance of this Privacy Policy**

Payzone respect your right to privacy and will not collect any personal information about you on the Site without your clear permission.

You can visit the Site without disclosing any personally identifiable information about you. By using any part of the Site you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy.

 **  
About Payzone**

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy "Payzone" means Payzone Ireland Ltd and any company or other entity within the group.

Payzone Ireland Ltd (hereinafter referred to as "Payzone" "us" "we" or "our") is committed to respecting your privacy and to complying with applicable Data Protection and privacy laws. Payzone Ireland Ltd is the “Data Controller” of all Data that is collected on the Site. Payzone is registered in Ireland with registration number 310110 and registered offices at Payzone, 4 Heather Road Sandyford Industrial Estate, Dublin 18, Ireland.

**Collection and Use of Personal Data  **

Personal Data means any information relating to you which allows us to identify you. When you visit or use the Site in any way we may collect and process different types of information about you.

Personal Data is Data that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you. This may include:

  1. Name
  2. Address
  3. Mobile number
  4. Email address
  5. Information about your use of our website and App
  6. The communications you exchange with us or direct to us via, emails, phone, webchat and social media

This Data that you volunteer to us will be processed for the following purposes:

  1. To contact you in response to communications you might send us
  2. To contact you from time to time via email or phone call in relation to the operation of a Merchant / Retailer account you may have with us
  3. To provide you with the information/service you have requested
  4. To provide information relating to a Merchant / Retailer account you may have with us
  5. To communicate with you, where consent has been given. Please note that Payzone will never share your details with any third parties for marketing purposes without clear consent and that you have the right to withdraw consent to direct marketing communications at any time and
  6. To send you email alerts and newsletters that you have opted-in to receive by filling in our online forms or contacting us by email or by other means.

**Your Rights**

This section outlines your rights as a Data Subject of Payzone. However, your rights may be restricted under the following circumstances

  * Where it’s necessary for the prevention, detection, investigation and prosecution of criminal offences
  * Where it’s necessary for the exercise or defence of a legal claim or proceedings.

Under certain circumstances, by law you have the right to:

 **Request Information**

| 

about whether we hold personal information about you, and, if so, what that information is and why we are holding or using it.  
  
---|---  
  
 **Request Access**

| 

to your Data ("Data Subject Access Request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal information (“Data”) we hold about you and to confirm that we are processing it legitimately.  
  
 **Request Correction**

| 

of the personal information that we hold about you. This enables you to have any inaccurate or incomplete Data we hold about you corrected.  
  
 **Request Erasure**

| 

of your Data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove Data where there is no reasonable explanation for us to continue to hold it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your Data where you have exercised your right to object to processing.  
  
 **Object to Profiling**

| 

that is not to be subject of any automated decision-making by us using your personal information or profiling of you  
  
 **Request the Restriction of Processing**

| 

of your personal information. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of Data about you.  
  
 **Request a Transfer**

| 

of your Data in an electronic and structured form to you or to another party (commonly known as a right to “Data Portability”).  
  
 **Withdraw Consent**

| 

In the limited circumstances where you may have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your Data for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time. Once we have received notification that you to withdraw your consent, we will stop processing your information for the purpose you originally agreed to, unless we have another legitimate basis for doing so in law.  
  
Requests for this information may be made by email to [dpo@payzone.ie](mailto:dpo@payzone.ie) or in writing to the Data Protection Officer, Payzone, Payzone House, 4 Heather Road, Sandyford Industrial Estate, Dublin 18.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access the information or to exercise any of your other rights. This is an appropriate security measure to ensure that personal information is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it.

This right only applies to your own Data. When exercising this right, please be as specific as possible.

**Retention**

Payzone will retain your Data for no longer than is necessary to fulfil the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We may also retain certain elements of your Data for a period after you close your account for our legitimate operations such as record keeping and to comply with our legal obligations. Whenever we retain your information we will do so in compliance with applicable laws.

**Links to other Sites**

Our Website may contain links to other websites which are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy (“Third-Party Websites”). If you access Third-Party Websites using the links provided, the operators of such sites may collect information from you which will be used by them in accordance with their own privacy policies, which may differ from ours. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those Third-Party Websites so that you understand if/how they collect and/or use information from you or your computer. 

**Security**

We endeavour to use appropriate technical and physical security measures to protect your Data. Any Data that you volunteer to Payzone, if retained, will be held on secure servers and will only be used to manage a Merchant / Retailer account you may have with us and to better our service offering.

We follow strict security procedures in the storage and disclosure of your Data, and to protect it against accidental loss or damage. The data you provide to us is protected using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) technology. SSL is the industry standard method of encrypting personal information and credit card details so that they can be securely transferred over the Internet. Payzone hold a Level 1 Payment Card Industry (PCI-DSS) certificate.

As effective as modern security practices are, no physical or electronic security system is entirely secure. The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. We will continue to revise policies and implement additional securities as new technologies become available.

In the event that there is an interception or unauthorised access to your Data, we will not be liable or responsible for any resulting misuse of your personal information.

 **Collection and Use of Non-Personal Data**

Like most websites, we gather statistical and analytical information collected on an aggregate basis of all visitors to our website. This non-personal data comprises of information that cannot be used to identify or contact you.

Like many sites, we use "cookies" to collect information. Cookies are files with small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a web site and stored on your computer's hard drive.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent.

Google Analytics uses cookies to help us analyse how users use our site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of payzone.ie includes your IP address. This information will be transmitted to and stored by Google on its servers. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity, and providing other services relating to Internet usage. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

Please visit the following pages for more information on Google Analytics [terms of use](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/terms/) and Google’s [privacy practices](https://privacy.google.com/).

**Disclosure of your Data**

We consider your Data to be private and confidential. Your Data may be shared within Payzone Ireland, for any of the purposes set out in this policy. We may disclose your Data to trusted third parties to send communications or carry out research. We require all third parties to have appropriate technical and operational security measures in place to protect your Data, in line with Irish and EU Data Protection Laws.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time and any changes to the statement will be communicated to you by way of an e-mail or a notice on our website. By continuing to use our Site after we post any such changes, you accept and agree to this Privacy Policy as modified.

**Complaints**

If you would like to make a complaint about how your Data is being processed by Payzone, or how your complaint has been handled, you have the right to lodge a complaint by email to [dpo@payzone.ie](mailto:dpo@payzone.ie) or in writing directly to;

Data Protection Officer  
Payzone Ireland,   
Payzone House,   
4 Heather Road,   
Sandyford Industrial Estate,   
Dublin 18.

You also have a right to complain to the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner at Canal House, Station Road, Portarlington, Co Laois or by telephone at 1890 25 22 31 and/or by email to [info@dataprotection.ie](mailto:info@dataprotection.ie)

Details of the Data Controller and Data Protection Officer      

For the purposes of the Data Protection legislation Payzone is the Data Controller of the Site.

If you have any questions, comments and requests about the information set out in this Privacy Policy, please contact the Payzone Data Protection Officer at:

Data Protection Officer  
Payzone Ireland,   
4 Heather Road,   
Sandyford Industrial Estate,   
Dublin 18.

01 2076000
